Let's give the choir another round of
applause.
>> Yes, sir.
>> What a blessing to be back in Houston.
Hear that crowd there.
Uh let's read the law, brothers and
sisters. Let's open our Bibles to Exodus
the 20th chapter.
Exodus 20.
Y'all know what verse we starting, man?
Oh no.
Verse one, Exodus 20 and one. We're
going to read the law, brothers and
sisters.
Read.
>> And God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I, the Lord thy God,
am a jealous God,
>> visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take thy name, take the
name of the Lord thy God, in vain, for
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day, to keep it holy. Six
days shalt thou labor and do all thy
work, but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt
not do any work, thou nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maidervant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not cover thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man's servant, nor his maid servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor anything that
is thy neighbor.
>> Praise the Lord. Ecclesiastes 12.
Ecclesiastes 12. We're going to read a
couple verses
cuz you go on YouTube, there's a lot of
things they got on there that what men
supposed to do, what the Lord want you
to do, and all the whole bunch of stuff.
Stuff you're supposed to wear and how
you supposed to look and supposed to
hang off your clothes.
Let's see what the book say. What a man
supposed to do.
>> Well,
read, brother.
Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter.
>> What it say?
>> Fear God and keep his commandments. For
this is the whole duty of man.
>> That is an absolute. Brothers and
sisters, keep reading.
>> For God shall bring every work into
judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil.
>> Praise ye the Lord. Revelations
do.
We're gonna pick it up. 22, I'm sorry.
22. Revelations 22. And we're going to
pick it up at verse 14.
22 and 14.
Revelations 22
and 14.
Got a couple up front up too. We got
some chairs up front up here.
A couple of the toes.
>> No toes. All right.
Let's read that. Read, brother.
Revelation 22 and 14. What it say?
>> Blessed are they that do his
commandments.
>> That know his commandments. that do his
>> Action. Read.
>> That they may have right to the tree of
life,
>> and may enter in through the gates, may
enter in through the gates into the
city.
>> Yes, sir.
>> For without are dogs, and sorcerers, and
whoreongers, and murderers, and
idolattors, and whosoever loveth and
maketh alive.
>> Praise the Lord for the reading of the
law, brothers and sisters.
>> Yeah. I'm glad everybody love the
reading of the law.
>> Praise the Lord. Uh I'm brother Roland.
Our reader today is brother the Paul.
And y'all know at the Israel of God we
teach by subject and title. And the
title of our lesson today is
understanding the fear of the Lord.
>> Understanding the fear of the Lord. Um
we did this lesson a couple of weeks ago
in Bible study on Wednesday night. If
you haven't been, you ought to come by,
get some little physical food and
spiritual food. But uh they want to say
let's go and do this for a Sabbath days
lesson. So that's what we going to do
today. All right.
>> Why understand the fear of the Lord?
Because you ask anybody, they say, I
love the Lord.
>> Right? And then I know you heard this
before. I can't serve nobody. I got to
fear.
>> You right. You sure don't serve him.
But we got to understand the word fear
of the Lord.
We think, we're always thinking that
carnal fear. We talking about the a man.
We talking about the fear of the Lord,
brothers and sisters. And that's what
we're going to look at today. But we're
going to jump this off because if you
are among those who fear the Lord,
you can be more comfortable, brothers
and sisters, if you're around some
people who fear the Lord. Well,
>> but if you around about that fear of the
Lord, who who everything's on the table,
>> right? Let's look at this. Genesis 20.
We're going to start off with some
examples. Genesis 20.
I still got that little in there that
Terrell
hear a little bit. Am I talking too
loud?
>> I'll work on that.
>> Know I'm back in Houston.
They think it's participation time or
something.
>> Genesis 20. Happy Sabbath, family.
>> Genesis 20 and we're going to pick it up
at verse
10.
Genesis 20 and verse 10. This is uh
Abraham when he was going to the land he
thought. He didn't know if they served
the Lord or not. So he told him that his
wife said well was who? His sister. He
didn't tell a whole lie, right? It was
>> you later. Well,
let's see what the book say.
Verse 10, brother, what it say?
>> And Aimilec said unto Abraham, "What so
thou that thou hast done this thing?"
>> Yeah. Because the Lord visited Aimilec
that night.
>> He was like, "I would I ain't touch it."
He said, "I know I prevented you from
touching them."
>> But Aimilec them, guess what? They
obviously knew the law, right?
>> And guess what? Those commandments even
before Mount Horab.
>> Read, brother.
And Abraham said, "Because I thought
surely the fear of God is not in this
place and they will slay me for my
wife's sake."
>> See, see that? He said, "Because surely
I thought that the what?" The fear of
God. Cuz we'll fear man, but we ain't
going to fear who?
>> And if you don't fear, if that land
didn't fear God, anything's on the
table.
>> Amen.
>> Anything's on the table.
So Abraham was trying to see, man, do
they fear God in this land? I ain't
think so. Let's go to Genesis 42. I mean
2 Kings.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Second Kings, right?
>> Keep it right today. You know,
2 Kings 17,
understanding the fear of the Lord.
Brothers and sisters, we're going to get
some examples out the way.
Starting off,
Genesis 17.
Second.
>> Yeah. I ain't gonna say it no more. I'm
gonna say next one. Y'all got them up
there.
I'm quickly correct.
Second Kings.
Second Kings 17
and we're going to pick up at verse 24.
and verse 24.
because
you got to have the fear of the Lord in
the land. Cuz if you don't have the fear
in the Lord in the land, you ain't going
to do right. And look what happened
here. This is uh when they removed the
children of Israel out of the land, they
put some uh strangers in there and the
Lord was dealing with them. Let's see
what happened. 24. What it say, brother?
And the king of Assyria brought man from
Babylon and from Katpa and from Ava and
from Ham and from Safarane and placed
them in the cities of Samaria instead of
the children of Israel.
>> So they had some uh imposters in there.
>> Read, brother.
>> And they possessed Samaria and dwelt in
the cities thereof.
>> So they living in the Lord's land and
dwelling in the cities thereof. She
can't just live in the Lord land and
just do you read, brother. And so it was
at the beginning of their dwelling there
that they feared not the Lord.
>> They feared not who?
>> The Lord.
>> Read.
>> Therefore the Lord sent lions among them
which slew some of them.
>> Hold on now. They fear not the Lord. He
sent who? What?
>> Lions.
>> Not killer bees. Not no bird. He sent
lions among them.
>> Read. Wherefore they spake to the king
of Assyria, saying, The nations which
thou hast removed, and placed in the
cities of Samaria, know not the manner
of the God of the land. Therefore, he
hath sent lions among them, and behold,
they slay them, because they know not
the manner of the God of the land.
>> Brothers and sisters, you better know
the manner of the God of Israel.
>> You better know the manner of the God of
Israel. Let's see. Let's keep reading.
What would it say? Then the king of
Assyria commanded, saying, "Carry
thither one of the priests whom ye
brought from Vince, and let them go and
dwell there, and let him teach them the
manner of the God of the land."
>> He said, "Go get the Holy Spirit, and
let him and take him to the land. Let
him let the Holy Spirit teach him,"
didn't he?
>> That ain't what he said.
>> Man work through man on the Lord going
to use man, ain't he?
>> He said, "Get one of the priests
>> and let him dwell there and let him
teach them." We got to learn through
who? through men, brothers and sisters.
That's
>> right.
>> The manner of the God of the land. Read.
>> Then one of the priests whom they had
carried away from Samaria came and dwelt
in Bethl.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And taught them how they should fear the
Lord.
>> Taught them how they should what?
>> Fear the Lord.
>> See, they taught them how they should
fear the Lord. Yes, sir.
>> So, that mean he gave them some
knowledge and some wisdom, brothers and
sisters.
>> Right.
>> We're going to see a little bit more of
that today. Another example,
Genesis 42,
understanding the fear of the Lord. If
you don't got the fear of the Lord, some
things can come upon you that's going to
tear you up, brothers and sisters.
>> Then after that, he going to wake you up
and throw you in that lake forever.
>> That's the one you don't want to be in.
and 15.
This when uh our forefathers,
they came to Egypt
and they left and they still had
everything in their bag. They were like,
"Oh my goodness." They had to go back
down uh to Egypt and they were nervous
cuz
they were like, "We ain't steal this."
>> It was in here,
>> but we're going to get something out of
this cuz we fear some things, right?
>> I'm going to show you. We're going to
find out who you should fear and who you
should not fear. That's what this lesson
going to really be about today.
>> Who you should fear and who you should
not fear.
>> Let's look at this, brother. Uh Genesis
42. Let's pick it up at verse 15.
42 and 15.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> Hereby ye shall be proved.
>> Hereby you shall be proved. Go ahead.
>> By the life of Pharaoh, you shall not go
forth hence except your youngest brother
come hither.
>> You ain't going to leave unless your
younger brother come.
>> Read.
>> Send one of you and let him fetch your
brother. and ye shall be kept in prison,
that your words may be proved, whether
there be any truth in you, or else by
the life of Pharaoh, surely ye are
spies.
>> Yeah. Because Joseph said, "Man, y'all
spies. He messing with his brothers,
right? Because of what they did to him,
right?" But they said, "Go fetch your
brother and we're going to we're going
to keep here. Go get your youngest
brother." Go ahead.
>> And he put them all together into ward
three days.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And Joseph said unto them the third day.
Now, this is what he told him on the
third day to give him a little comfort.
>> What'd he say?
>> This do and live for I fear God.
>> So you do this and live for I do what?
>> Fear God.
>> And guess what that means, man? Let's
make sure we do what he say cuz he going
to do what he says.
>> Yes, sir.
>> If we tell if do what he told us to do,
he going to do what he said he was going
to do. He going to do his part. Why?
Because he does what?
>> Fear God, brother. That's the way we
should be.
>> Amen.
>> If you say something, it should be done.
Why? because you do what?
>> Your word should be true, brothers and
sisters.
>> That's right.
>> Just don't be running your mouth just
because you got a mouthpiece.
>> A lot of that go on now.
>> Genesis 43. We finished that.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Genesis 43
and we're going to pick up at verse 19.
Because when they left,
he told them they left. He told them to
go back and one of them stayed. They
looked in their bag. They still had
everything in that bags. They're like,
"Oh man, what happened?" They going to
think we Oh, they have to go back down
there. So when they go back, they going
to try to talk to the uh to uh Joseph's
steward of the house.
Genesis 43. And we're going to pick up
at verse 19.
>> Yes, sir.
>> What it say, brother? And they came near
to the steward of Joseph's househ, and
they communed with him at the door of
the househ, and said, "Oh sir, we came
indeed down at the first time to buy
food."
>> Yes, sir.
>> And it came to pass when we came to the
end that we opened our sacks, and
behold, every man's money was in the
mouth of his sack, our money in full
weight, and we have brought it again in
our hand. Man, they still they brought
all their money right back down there
cuz they didn't the first time they
went, they got all their food and went
to pay for it. But when they got to the
end, they checked their bags, they still
had all their money plus the stuff they
had asked for.
Keep reading, brother.
>> And our money have we brought down in
our hands to buy food. We cannot tell
who put our money in our sacks.
>> Man, we don't know who put that money
back in our sacks. We didn't
>> read, brother.
>> And he said,
>> what did he say?
>> Peace be to you. Peace be to you.
>> Fear not.
>> Fear what?
>> Fear not. Fear not who man. Brothers and
sisters, fear not what this man going to
do to you cuz you got this money in your
bag. Read
>> your God and the God of your father have
given you treasure in your sacks. I had
your money and he brought Simeon out
unto them.
>> He said he had your had your money and
he then he brought his brother out to
him. Cuz we're going to find out today
who to fear and who not to fear because
they were in fear of the Egyptian
at that time,
>> right?
>> Cuz they like, "Man, we got all this
money back. Sir, what can we do, right?
Better get that favorite two-letter word
and deal with these men, right?"
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's keep moving. Psalms
>> Proverbs 30. Next one.
Proverbs 30.
Proverbs 30. [snorts]
What does it say, brother? 30 and5.
Proverbs 30 and verse 5. What it say?
>> Every word of God is pure.
>> Every word, not some of it. Absolutely.
Every word of God is pure. Read.
>> He is a shield unto them that put their
trust in him.
>> He is a shield unto them that do what?
>> Put their trust in him. and fear him cuz
you ain't going to trust him unless you
do what?
>> Fear him. They go right hand in hand,
brothers and sisters. Right.
>> Hand in hand. Let's keep moving. We
finish that.
>> No. Six.
>> Oh, six. My bad. Read.
>> Add thou not unto his word.
>> Lest what?
>> Lest he reprove thee, and thou be found
a liar.
>> So, you got to be have some fear cuz I
know y'all ain't going to add unto the
word. Not if you got that fear. If you
ain't got that feel, you say all kind of
stuff.
>> Add, subtract, multiply, and divide.
>> Until you get to that later, things
going to change.
>> We finished that.
>> Yes, sir. It is.
>> Proverbs 1. Proverbs 1
and we're going to pick up at verse
five. Understand the fear of the Lord,
brothers and sisters. Understand the
fear of the Lord because the man God
knows his creation. People you love you
to cross 100,000 times.
>> Well, 990,000 times.
Uhoh. Start over. Let's go back to uh
phone still. We got to start over.
>> Proverbs 1 and verse five. What it say,
brother?
>> A wise man will hear.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And will increase learning. A man of
understanding shall attain unto wise
counsel.
>> Man, it's talking about having big ears.
Y'all see that? That mouth got to get
small and them ears got to get bigger.
>> Right.
>> Read.
>> To understand the proverb and the
interpretation, the words of the wise
and their dark say.
>> How you going to do all that if you
ain't listening?
>> Read, brother. The fear of the Lord is
the beginning of knowledge.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But fools despise wisdom and
instruction.
>> Man, that is something else right there.
>> The fear of the Lord is the beginning of
what?
>> Knowledge.
>> Knowledge. Cuz when you find out who you
dealing with,
your knees start shaking like the leaves
in the trees
>> and your car keys. That's what your
knees start doing. You find out who you
dealing with. The God of Abraham, the
God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob. The
one who flooded the whole world except
eight people, brothers and sisters.
>> Y so you find out who you dealing with.
>> Read, brother.
>> He doesn't.
>> That was it.
>> Seven.
>> That was seven. Okay.
>> Yes, sir. Skipping to 22.
>> Yes, sir. Proverbs.
Skip down to 22 cuz I want to show you
something.
It said to fear the Lord, didn't it?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's see what 22 says. Read. How long
ye simple ones will ye love simplicity?
And the scorners delight in their
scorning and fools hate knowledge.
>> So if you hate knowledge, you ain't
going to never get that what? Fear.
>> Cuz fear is the beginning of wisdom. So
if you don't want to get that knowledge
about the holy one, you ain't going to
get that fear of the holy one.
>> Cuz fools do what? Hate knowledge. Read,
brother.
>> Turn you at my reproof.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Behold, I will pour out my spirit unto
you.
>> Yes, sir. I will make known my words
unto you.
>> I will make known my what?
>> Words.
>> My words unto you. Read.
>> Because I have called and ye refuse.
>> I have stretched out my hand and no man
regarded.
>> I stretch out my hand and no man regard
it. Go ahead.
>> But ye have set at not all my counsel
and would none of my reproof.
>> You ain't going to deal with nothing
that I have for you.
>> He saidnone of my reproof. And that none
means absolutely absolutely what nothing
>> you want to do who you praise the Lord.
Lord gave you that option though. But
guess what? It's come consequences for
that.
>> Right.
>> Read, brother.
>> I also will laugh at your calamity.
>> I will mock when you when your fear
cometh.
>> Oh, you got some fear, but it ain't of
who?
>> The Lord.
>> I'm He going to mock when your fear
come. You got fear, but it ain't fear of
who? The Lord. Brothers and sisters,
read, brother. When your fear cometh as
desolation, and your destruction cometh
as a whirlwind, when distress and
anguish cometh upon you,
>> Yes, sir.
>> then shall they call upon me,
>> but I will not answer.
>> I ain't going to answer the head.
>> They shall seek me early, but they shall
not find me.
>> They going to seek them and they ain't
going to find them.
>> Why, brother?
>> What it say?
>> For that they hated knowledge.
>> They hated knowledge and what? and did
not choose the fear of the Lord.
>> They chose some fear, but they didn't
choose the fear of what?
>> The Lord.
>> They chose the fear of man, the fear
that of destruction, the fear of the
whirlwind
or distress and anguish. That's what you
fear.
>> Fear of the Lord. Oh, no. I ain't never
seen him.
>> Skip down, my brother,
to 30 and three. What it say? But who so
hearkeneth unto me shall dwell safely.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And shall be quiet from fear of evil.
>> Yeah. Because he ain't even gonna fear
evil.
>> Why am I going to fear evil? The God I
serve created evil. Right.
>> Why you going to fear evil? The God I
serve created evil. He said, "I the Lord
did all these things." Brothers and
sisters,
better find out who you who you serving.
>> Yes, sir.
Deuteronomy
because we got to look at fear. Not who
not to fear.
>> You know, we got some fear, but we'll
show you who not to fear. Go to the next
one. I ain't even going to say it.
>> And we're going to pick up at verse one.
>> Whatever it say on the screen.
Deuteronomy 31
and 1.
Look what the Lord Look what Moses told
the children of Israel right here before
they get ready to go over into the land.
What the Lord's promised unto them.
>> Read, brother.
>> And Moses went and spake these words
unto all Israel.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And he said unto them, I am 120 years
old this day. I can no more go out and
come in. Also the Lord hath said unto
me, thou shalt not go over in this
Jordan.
>> He already Lord said he going to lay me
down. I ain't going over that land with
y'all.
>> But I got some information for you.
>> Read, brother.
>> The Lord thy God, he will go over before
thee, and he will destroy these nations
from before thee, and thou shalt possess
them. and Joshua, he shall go over
before thee as the Lord hath said.
>> Hold on. If the Lord going to go over
before thee, who should you fear? The
Lord of the people in the land.
>> The Lord cause if he going over before,
he said he going to destroy them, didn't
he?
>> Read, brother.
>> And the Lord shall do unto them as he
did to Sad and to Og, kings of the
Amorites, and unto the land land of them
whom he destroyed.
>> Go ahead. And the Lord shall give them
up before your face, that ye may do unto
them according unto all the commandments
which I have commanded you.
>> He going to do unto them according to
all the commands I commanded you. Now
look what he tell them. Go ahead.
>> Be strong.
>> Be strong
>> and of good courage.
>> And be of good courage. Go ahead.
>> Fear not.
>> Fear what?
>> Fear not who? The man of the land.
>> Right.
>> Don't fear man.
>> Don't fear a man, brothers and sisters.
Start it over.
>> Be strong. Uhhuh.
>> And of good courage.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Fear not, nor be afraid of them.
>> Of them.
>> Of them. Go ahead.
>> For the Lord thy God, he it is that
doeth go with thee. He will not fail
thee, nor forsake thee.
>> That's some faith right there. You got
to have that faith, brothers and
sisters, that the Lord is with if the
Lord is with you. How you know if the
Lord with you? If you with him,
>> right?
Not cause you breathing.
>> I'm breathing the Lord with me. No.
>> No.
>> How you know you with he with you? Cuz
you with him, brothers and sisters.
>> We finished that.
>> You want to go to eight?
>> Yes, sir. Keep reading.
>> And Moses called unto Joshua, and said
unto him, in the sight of all Israel,
>> in sight of all of Israel, go ahead.
>> Be strong.
>> Be strong
>> and of good courage.
>> Uhhuh. For thou must go with this people
unto the land which the Lord hath sworn
unto their fathers to give them.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And thou shalt cause them to inherit it.
>> You going to cause them to inherit it.
Keep reading.
>> And the Lord, he it is that doeth go
before thee.
>> He will be with thee. He will not fail
thee, neither forsake thee. Fear not,
neither be dismayed.
>> Man, come on now. But you got to have
faith to have that fear not. See that
fear not came after that. That's a
condition right now.
>> Yes sir.
>> That's a condition. If you have faith,
fear not.
>> If you got faith, fear God.
>> Right.
Joshua.
>> Hey. Oh, that what y'all got? Ha.
>> I got it up there. I added that.
That team too good back there.
Eight and one one verse.
These are for iron examples, brothers
and sisters.
81. What did it say, brother? And the
Lord said unto Joshua,
>> Uhhuh.
>> Fear not.
>> Fear not what?
>> Neither be thou dismayed.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Take all the people of war with thee,
and arise. Go up to I. See, I have given
into the ha into thy hand the king of I,
and his people, and his city, and his
land.
>> That's when your Lord told him, "Fear
not, because this guy we knocked out
Jericho." He said, "Go on up to Ai and
fear not cuz I done gave them to you."
However, your uh your your uh
transgression cause a little small
nation to put knots in your head. Right.
>> Right.
>> It's called with consequences, brother.
Exodus one.
Well, they good.
Exodus 1 and we're going to pick up at
verse 15.
Who to fear and who not to fear. We're
looking at who not fear not. We're
looking at who not to fear right here.
Yeah.
Better right there.
Exodus 1 and 15. What did it say,
brother?
>> And the king of Egypt spake to the
Hebrew midwives.
>> The who of Egypt?
>> The king.
>> This the king. You got to give reverence
to the king, don't you?
>> He told them, "Look, go speak to the
midwife." What' he tell them?
>> Of which the name of the one was
Shiffra, and the name of the other poor.
Mhm.
>> And he said, "When ye do the office of a
midwife to the Hebrew women, and see
them upon the stools, if it be a son,
then ye shall kill him. But if it be a
daughter, then she shall live."
>> Hold on now. This the king now. Oh, king
live forever.
>> Right? But the king tell you to do
something contrary to the king of kings.
>> You tell that little king, little K,
can't do that. Can't do that little K. I
don't care. Hey, if you kill me, little
K, you got to do it. But I can't go
against the big king,
>> the king of kings, right?
>> Read, brother.
>> But the midwives feared God.
>> They did what?
>> Feared God.
>> See, that's what you got to have. You
got the midwives feared God. Read.
>> And did not as the king of Egypt
commanded them.
>> He commanded them and they did not do
what the king of Egypt commanded them.
Why? Cuz they fear who?
>> God.
>> Read, brother. but save the men children
alive.
>> Go ahead.
>> And the king of Egypt called for the
midwives and said unto them, Why have ye
done this thing and have saved the men
children alive?
>> Well, why you've done this? I commanded
you. Now, what they say?
>> And the midwives said unto Pharaoh,
"Because the Hebrew women are not as the
Egyptian women." Yes, sir.
>> For they are lively and are delivered
heir the midwife.
>> And you said, "Oh, you said what?" I'm
sorry. I got distracted. It says, "For
they are lively."
>> Yes, sir.
>> And are delivered air. The midwives come
in unto them.
>> Yes, sir. Cuz they live loud. They ain't
going to let you go in there to do
nothing like that,
>> right?
>> Not with that neck and that hand.
>> Read, brother.
>> Therefore, God dealt well with the
>> God dealt what?
>> Dealt well.
>> The king couldn't DO NOTHING WITH HIM.
>> HE disobeyed the order of the king cuz
they feared who?
>> God. And the king couldn't do nothing
with them. But God did what? Dealt well
with him. What he do, brother?
>> And the people multiplied and waxed very
mighty.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And it came to pass because the midwives
feared God.
>> Because the midwives feared God. What?
>> That he made them houses.
>> And they got a little fat warm on the
beach
>> right next to the uh pyramid. I don't
know.
But they got a house
>> right
>> on the beach. You got a house in the
sand
>> because they did what? Feared God.
>> So that tells me there's some benefits
to fearing the Lord.
>> And I'm telling you one benefit. There's
eternal benefit for fearing the Lord,
brothers and sisters.
>> Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Where we at, Prop?
>> That was it.
>> Yes, sir. Judges
>> Judges 6.
Boy, they good.
Judges 6
and we're going to pick up at verse 6.
But you fear God in vain if you ain't
obeying him, right?
>> You know why? Because you really ain't
fearing him.
Judges 6 and6.
What does it say, brother?
>> And Israel was greatly impoverished
because of the Midianites. And the
children of Israel cried unto the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And it came to pass when the children of
Israel cried unto the Lord because of
the Midianites that the Lord sent a
prophet unto the children of the
Israelites.
>> He sent a prophet to inform them what
their uh
what he's done and what their response
to what he's done to for them. Go ahead.
>> Which said unto them, Thus sayeth the
Lord God of Israel, I brought you up
from Egypt, and brought you forth out of
the house of bondage.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And I delivered you out of the hand of
the Egyptians.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And out of the hand of all that
oppressed you, and drove them out before
from before you, and gave you their
land.
>> The Lord is showing his resume what he
did for us, brothers and sisters.
>> Read. And I said unto you, I am the Lord
your God. Fear not the gods of the
Amorites, in whose land ye dwell, but ye
have not obeyed my voice.
>> Man,
we going to fear everything. We fear,
man, he may not come down my chimney.
>> Don't fear the God of these lands,
brothers and sisters.
>> Cuz rabbits don't have colorful chicken
eggs.
They go evaporated like that water
outside right now on that Houston
concrete.
>> That was it.
>> Because you didn't fear not the God. He
said, "Fear not the gods of the land."
But guess what?
>> We will not do what? Obey his voice.
>> Will not obey his voice. Brothers and
sisters, to obey is better than what?
>> Sacrifice.
>> Man, you got to do it.
You know, I'mma sacrifice a little time.
I'm I'mma sacrifice my hair. Anything.
>> Where we at?
>> That was in
>> end of uh judges.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Acts 27.
Acts 27.
>> Yeah, I had all of y'all sheet.
>> Y'all get off my my lesson. Y'all don't
worry about that sheet over there on
that paper.
>> They ain't got that one on there. Yes, I
even got this. My bad, Don.
>> Acts 27.
Probably got it on his right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Acts 27. And we're going to pick it up
at verse one.
27 and one because we're going to read a
little bit about this. understanding the
fear of the Lord. This when Paul, they
gonna take Paul to Rome right here.
Read, brother. And when it was
determined that we should sail unto
Italy, they delivered Paul and certain
other prisoners unto one named Julius, a
centurion of Augustus band.
>> Skip down to verse four and read.
>> And when we had launched from Vince, we
sailed under Cyprus because the winds
were contrary.
>> The winds were what?
>> Contrary. So the wind is a little
contrary but they they going to get in
there anyhow. Skip down brother to verse
seven and read.
>> And when we had sailed slowly many days
and scarce were scarce were come over
against snidas the wind not suffering us
we sailed under cit over against Salmon.
So the wind is preventing them. Keep
reading.
>> And hardly passing it came unto a place
which is called the fair he havens. Nigh
where unto was the city of Li.
>> The city of what?
>> Le.
>> Go ahead.
>> Now when much time was spent and when
sailing was now dangerous because the
fast was now already passed, Paul
admonished them.
>> Paul going to tell them something. All
right. Now read. and said unto them,
"Sears, I perceive that this voyage will
will be with hurt and much damage, not
only of the lady and ship, but also of
our lives."
>> Paul said, "All right, now you know the
wind going to be crazy. I think this
voyage going to be a tough voyage. We
may lose some of our supplies, this
ship, and some of the lives of the
people on this boat on this on this
ship."
>> Right?
>> Read, brother. Nevertheless, the
centurion believed the master and the
owner of the ship more than those things
which were spoken by Paul.
>> Ain't that right? They don't believe
nothing about no servant of the Lord.
>> They ain't going to believe. I believe
the master. Right. Skip down, my
brother, to verse 18 and read.
>> And we being exceedingly tossed with the
tempest, the next day they lightened the
ship.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the third day we cast out with our
own hands the tackling of the ship. He
told you you're going to lose some of
your stuff in it.
>> They start throwing stuff out. Go ahead.
>> And when neither sun nor stars in many
days appeared, and no small tempest lay
on us, all hope that we should be saved
was then taken away.
>> Man, they like, man, the weather that is
about to
is going on,
>> right? You in that ship, you threw
everything over. You ain't seen the sun
or the stars in days.
>> Huh?
Read, brother.
>> But after long abstinence, Paul stood
forth in the midst of them.
>> Oh, oh, hold on, fellas. I want to let
y'all know something right here. Read
>> and said, "Sir,
>> sir,
>> see, ye should sers.
>> Sears,
[laughter]
>> sir."
>> Yes, sir.
>> Potato potato.
>> Ye should have hearkened unto me.
>> You should have hearkened unto me.
Listen with the intent to do. Go ahead.
>> And not have loed from cit.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And to have gained this harm and loss.
>> Now you gained this harm and loss. But
go ahead.
>> And now I exhort you to be of good
cheer.
>> Don't worry. Be of good cheer. I'm going
to let y'all know something. Read.
>> For there shall be no loss of any man's
life among you, but of the ship.
>> We're going to lose some of this ship
and some of the supplies, but nobody's
life is going to be lost.
>> Read. For there stood by me this night
the angel of God.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Whose I am and whom I serve.
>> Oh, so whose I am and whom I serve? The
angel of who? The God of Abraham, the
God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob.
Read, brethren,
>> saying, Fear not, Paul, thou must be
brought before Caesar. And lo, God hath
given thee all them that sail with thee.
>> Man, the Lord told you, guess what? You
shouldn't even fear. Guess what starts
Monday? hurricane season.
>> So,
>> don't fear the weather. Serve your God.
Who in control of it? I could we could
have we if we' have read a little bit of
that, we just told you the names of the
wind. The Lord named them.
>> He named the wind.
>> So, who you going to fear, brothers and
sisters? Fear God. Don't fear the
weather. Don't fear the dancing weather
person. Don't fear none of that. Fear
God, brothers and sisters.
>> Yes, sir. That's whom you shall fear,
right? Yes,
>> sir.
>> Where at?
>> 25.
>> 25. What it say?
>> Wherefore, sir, be of good cheer. For I
believe God.
>> That I what?
>> Believe God.
>> Uh-huh.
>> That it shall be even as it was told me.
>> So, you ain't got to worry about when
you fear God, you believe that word.
>> Yes, sir.
>> When you fear God, you believe that
word.
>> That's the end of that one, brother.
Genesis 15. That's right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. Genesis 15.
>> We almost done. I had to add some more
scriptures. We ain't got but like 18
more.
>> It was a short lesson.
I ain't want to get y'all here too early
on the Lord's Sabbath day.
one one verse brother
just after Abraham just finished uh
fight dealing with the kings
and measedc
came and came to him
and after all this stuff this happened
verse 15 and one verse I mean chapter 15
verse one what it say brother
>> after the after these things the word of
the Lord The Lord came unto Abram in a
vision saying
>> what he say
>> fear not Abram I am thy shield and thy
exceeding great reward.
>> See you can't fear man. Don't fear man.
Thus will fear not. Don't fear man.
Don't fear all because he is your exce.
He is your what? I am thy shield and thy
exceeding great reward. If he your
shield, what can touch you?
>> Nothing.
>> He'll touch you.
>> But can't nobody else touch it. So who
you going to fear, brothers and sisters?
>> Him, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Psalms three.
We should be back on track on your paper
now,
>> unless I throw something else out there
a little later.
Psalms 3
and we're going to pick up at verse one.
1 through 02.
That's eight.
I do like the Hebrew. They can speak one
word in in Hebrew and 75 others in
English
cuz I know as much Spanish as they know
Hebrew.
Three in one, brother.
What it say?
>> Lord, how are they increased that
trouble me?
>> Lord, how are they increase that
trouble? We talking about those who to
fear not. Go ahead. Many are they that
rise up against me.
>> You got many. Go ahead.
>> Many there be which say of my soul,
there is no help from him in God. Say
lie.
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> But thou, oh Lord, art a shield for me,
my glory, and the lifter up of mine
head.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I cried unto the Lord with my voice, and
he heard me out of his holy hill.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I laid me down and slept. I awake, for
the Lord sustained me. For the Lord is
your shash, and he shall sustain thee.
Brothers and sisters, read, brother.
>> I will not be afraid of 10 thousands of
people that have set themselves against
me round about.
>> Oh, you got 10,000. All y'all against
me? 1 2 3 4 9. Okay. All y'all against
me.
>> So,
>> that's what he just said right here,
didn't he? I will not be afraid of
10,000 people that set themselves round
about against me.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Read, brother.
>> Arise, O Lord. Uh-huh.
>> Save me,
>> sir.
>> Oh my God. For thou hast smitten all
mine enemies upon thyon on the cheek
upon the cheekbone. Thou hast broken the
teeth of the ungodly.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Salvation belongth unto the Lord. Thy
blessing is upon thy people, say Lot.
>> I don't care how many come against you,
brothers and sisters. You stick with
serving your God and fearing him.
>> Him only shall I fear. Right.
>> Right.
10,000 that it's not enough.
>> One angel killed how many? A 100,000 in
one night.
Come on. It's not enough.
Better send two.
>> What we got next?
>> Psalm 27.
>> Psalm 27. I got too many papers up here.
Psalm 27.
And we're going to pick up at verse one.
We talk about we still looking at fear
not. Brothers and sisters, you see all
these examples of who not to fear,
>> but we fear a lot.
>> How you know if you fear the Lord? By
your actions. Well,
>> we're going to see that.
27 and verse one. What it say, brother?
>> The Lord is my light and my salvation.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Whom shall I fear?
>> Yes sir.
>> The Lord is the strength of my life. Of
whom shall I be afraid?
>> Those are some good questions.
>> And the answer is like Keith Swear said,
nobody.
>> Nobody, brothers and sisters.
>> Nobody.
Read.
>> When the wicked, even my enemies and my
foes, came upon me to eat up my flesh,
>> they stumbled and fell.
>> Hold on. I ain't do nothing to them.
They just stumbled. They coming up on me
and they stumbled and fell.
>> He didn't say, "I put my hands on them."
He said, "They stumble and fail."
>> Three against one.
Who is in trouble? The three. Ain't that
right, Paul?
>> Three against one. The three in trouble
cuz I don't fear man.
All three of them.
>> All three of them. And like, man, did I
get a wrinkle?
>> Where we at?
>> Three.
>> Read.
>> Though an host should encamp against me.
>> A host shall encamp against me. What's
that?
>> My heart shall not fear.
>> My heart shall not fear. You can't be
fearing man. Brothers and sisters.
>> Read.
>> Though war should rise against me.
>> Uhhuh.
>> In this will I be confident.
>> I ain't even afraid of war. Cuz I got to
fear who? My God.
>> Keep reading, brother.
>> One thing have I desired of the Lord.
>> What's that?
>> That will I seek after, that I may dwell
in the house of the Lord all the days of
my life.
>> Uhhuh.
>> To behold the beauty of the Lord, and to
inquire in his temple.
>> Yes, sir. Verse five.
>> For in the time of trouble, he shall
hide me in his pavilion. And the secret
of his tabernacle shall he hide me. He
shall set me up upon a rock.
>> Man, did he say he's your shield?
>> He gonna hide you. He gonna protect you,
>> right?
>> If you fear him. Why? Cuz if you fear
him, you going to what? Obey him.
>> The obeying get you the benefits,
brothers and sisters. Not just the
knowledge. The knowledge don't get you
the benefit.
>> The obeying of it gets you the benefit.
>> And obey comes with the fear, right?
Yes, sir.
Luke,
>> what? Yes, sir.
>> Luke 12.
I know he got to
lift all kind of weights and look strong
on the outside,
muscles coming out of his neck and
eyeballs and everything. soul.
So, don't care if you got a toe muscle.
I don't care. My
>> God, I know a God.
[snorts] I know a God. I bet he ain't
bigger than bigger than uh who David
whoop up on.
>> That Philistine Goliath,
>> uncircumcised Philistine.
>> Y'all better understand. We got to fear
this God, brothers. It ain't a It's a
blessing to fear this Lord, brothers and
sisters.
I can't serve nobody I can fear. Let's
see.
>> 12 and four. What it say, brother?
>> And I say unto you, my friend.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Be not afraid of them that kill the
body, and after that have no more that
they can do.
>> Oh, did y'all hear that?
>> Y'all missed the key word. You heard
what he called you.
>> Start that over.
>> And I say unto you, my friend.
>> My who? friend.
>> Man, he ain't call you no servant. He
call you his friends.
>> That's what you want to be a friend of
God, brothers and sisters.
>> Read.
>> Be not afraid of them that kill the
body.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And after that have no more that they
can do.
>> All you can do is kill me once.
>> Sorry.
>> You all you can do is shoot me once.
>> After that, you can't do anything else
>> cuz you got to get judged like I got to
get judged.
Read, brother.
>> But I will forewarn you whom ye shall
fear.
>> I'mma tell you whom ye shall fear. We We
pass to fear not. Let's see who we shall
fear right here. Read, brother.
>> Fear him.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Which after he hath killed hath power to
cast into hell. Yeah. I say unto you,
fear him.
>> I don't even need to talk after that
one,
>> but I am. [laughter]
>> Fear him, brothers and sisters.
See the one that going to raise you up,
judge you, and throw you in that fire.
>> Raise you up.
>> And you going to be in the same line
with the one who who uh who shot you
first. Hey, how you doing, brother? How
you doing?
>> You in the line with me.
>> You may get the same reward,
>> right?
>> I may get in the kingdom though
>> cuz we all going to be what? Judge,
brothers and sisters.
But
>> that's who you shall fear. Proverbs 9.
Proverbs 9
and we're going to pick up at verse 10.
Proverbs 9 and 10.
>> Verse nine, what it say?
>> Give instruction to a wise man.
>> Uhhuh. And he will and he will be yet
wiser.
>> Yes sir.
>> Teach a just man and he will increase
and learn.
>> I'm tell you because you got big ears.
>> That's what we supposed to have big
ears. But most time we just want to tell
somebody what we know.
>> That's how you know the difference
between the two. That's how you know the
difference. Sometimes people are always
here here to listen. They going to
listen right
>> and then respond. But some people all
they want to do is tell and teach what
they know. You teach people by your
walk, brothers and sisters. That is the
best teacher you can have right there.
>> Not that mouth.
>> What it say?
>> The fear of the Lord is the beginning of
wisdom.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the knowledge of the holy is
understanding.
>> I thought it said fear is beginning of
knowledge.
>> Guess what? When you find out, you've
been reading, you getting to know like,
oh my goodness. Now you know who you
dealing with, right? But then that
wisdom also tells you that what I got
some I mean that that fear tells I got
some wisdom too cuz I need I fear him.
>> So fear is the beginning of knowledge
and wisdom. It's the beginning of both
of them brothers and sisters
>> and knowledge of the holy. Oh yeah
that's understanding now cuz you going
to start what? Doing.
>> You going to start doing. That's your
understanding brothers and sisters. your
your action, your walk, your fruit.
Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> We finished that.
>> Let's keep moving.
>> Moving on down. Isaiah 29.
Been working [snorts] in the choir.
My
>> Isaiah 29
and we're going to pick up at verse 9.
and nine.
Why are we in this state?
Why ain't no fear? Why is just love?
>> Cuz everybody love, right?
>> I love the Lord.
>> He heard my cry.
>> That's a song, ain't
>> now. What it say, brother?
>> Stay yourselves and wonder.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Cry ye out and cry.
>> Yes, sir.
>> They are drunken, but not with wine.
They stagger, but not with strong drink.
>> This is not a physical drunk.
>> That's right. This is a spiritual drunk
right here, brothers and sisters. Read,
brother.
>> For the Lord hath poured out upon you
the spirit of deep sleep and have closed
your eyes. The prophets and your rulers,
the seers, have he covered.
>> Hold on now. The Lord did this
>> because they don't fear.
If you don't fear him, cover them up.
>> Right.
But I got I got big degrees.
Read.
>> And the vision of all is become unto you
as the words of a book that is sealed.
>> It's the words of a book that is sealed.
Read, brother.
>> Which man deliver to one that is
learned, saying, read this, I pray thee.
>> You mean the one that's learned got all
kind of alphabets behind their name,
>> in front and behind?
Then he said what? Read this. I pray
thee. What did it say?
>> And he saith, I cannot, for it is
sealed.
>> Yeah. Because your degrees and your job
is your curse.
>> Don't put your everything on your curse,
brothers and sisters.
>> Come on now.
>> Go. That's your curse. Your job is to
serve God and keep his commandments,
brothers and sisters.
>> Where we at, brother?
>> 13.
>> Read.
>> Wherefore the Lord said,
>> Uhhuh. For as much as this people draw
near me with their mouth,
>> oh, you know, we can run our mouth,
Lord, Lord, Lord, Lord,
>> Lord, Lord, Lord, Lord.
>> Read.
>> And with their lips do, honor me.
>> Oh, going kisses and loving and talking
salt.
Hey everybody,
praise the Lord. Till you say something,
they don't like they get to I thought
all that nice stuff.
read.
>> But have removed their heart far from
me.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And their fear toward me is taught by
the precept of men.
>> Oh, they got fear for the Lord, but it
ain't talk, it ain't coming from here.
They fear coming from where? The
precepts of men.
>> And they don't ever say the Lord did
anything wrong.
>> Only time they use uh when they want to
judge you or stop you from doing
something. That's the only time they
going to use the Bible.
>> Right.
>> Right. We finished that.
>> Yes, sir. Yes, sir. Let's keep it
moving. Deuteronomy five.
What did our forefathers say?
Cuz it ain't about that mouthpiece. You
will say anything with that mouthpiece.
Deuteronomy 5.
Deuteronomy 5. We're going to pick up at
verse 27. What did our forefathers say?
And the Lord already knew.
read.
>> Go thou near and hear all that the Lord
our God shall say, and speak thou unto
us all that the Lord our God shall speak
unto thee, and he will hear it and do
it.
>> We love one. Hey, let you tell let the
Lord tell you and you come tell us what
he said and then we'll listen to you.
>> We love the middleman, don't we?
We got this book right now that the same
word right here. The words right here.
Why not use this?
I was talking to a brother the other day
and he was saying that he read the book.
He don't really but he said man when I
was I was going to Sunday church and I
was sitting there. I'm like man that he
was like he said that ain't what the
book say though.
>> But he didn't know the truth. He didn't
know where to get the truth. But he say
he's in there but he like man that ain't
what the book say though.
>> Ain't that something? If you read first,
you can't be deceived, brothers and
sisters. Because if you know, her going
to deceive you. If you know,
>> brother Ro, I like your hair.
>> Who going to see? Who going to see me
like that?
I already know.
Where we at, brother?
>> We at uh 28.
>> Start at the top.
>> Read.
>> Go thou near. We at 27.
>> 27. Go here.
>> Go thou near and hear all that the Lord
our God shall say.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And speak thou unto us all that the Lord
our God shall speak unto thee. And he
and we will hear it and do it.
>> We supposed. We told them we going to
hear it and we going to what?
>> Do it. We going to hear it and we're
going to do it. What the Lord say?
>> And the Lord heard the voice of your
word.
>> Uhhuh.
>> When ye spake unto me, and the Lord said
unto me,
>> listen to what the Lord said to our
forefathers, brothers and sisters. Read.
>> I have heard the voice of the words of
this people which they have spoken unto
thee. They have well said all that they
have spoken.
>> They have I mean they said it so nice.
They have well said all that they have
spoken. Read.
>> Oh, that there was such an heart in
them. Oh, if it was such a what?
>> Heart in them.
>> Man, if it was such a heart in them.
Read.
>> That they would fear me and keep all my
commandments always that it might be
well with them and with their children
forever.
>> You want to do right by YOUR CHILDREN?
KEEP HIS COMMANDMENTS.
>> Don't try to get no job and leave no
money for them.
>> What they going to do with that?
>> Spend it.
>> What they going to do with that $20 you
left for them?
>> WE AIN'T GOT NOTHING. WE AIN'T GOT NO
MONEY. We going to leave $20.
Well,
>> I'm bad. I ain't got no money. Y'all may
have something to leave for y'all. Don't
speak on others.
>> Proverbs 16.
>> Yes, sir.
How? Okay. Our forefathers did that and
they got dirty. HOW DO YOU GET CLEANED
UP THEN?
>> YEAH, it's there. Because what?
You can read it and you're still dirty.
So what good is that?
>> Let the word of God the word of God wash
myself at this Bible.
>> That ain't going to clean you up.
>> Let's see what it say.
Proverbs 16 and we're going to pick up
at verse six
>> oh
six and seven.
>> Yes sir.
>> Now
read. By mercy and truth, iniquity is
purged.
>> By mercy and truth, iniquity is purged.
Read.
>> And by the fear of the Lord,
>> men will depart from evil.
>> And by the fear of the Lord, what?
>> Men will depart from
>> If you ain't even fear the Lord, you
ain't going to depart from evil. If you
just love the Lord, you going to keep
doing what you doing.
>> Why? Cuz you what? Love the Lord.
That's why you going to do that. It says
verse seven, what it say, brother?
>> When a man's ways please the Lord,
>> when a man ways please the Lord, what
>> he maketh even his enemies to be at
peace with him.
>> He make even his enemies to be at peace
with him.
>> So whom shall ye fear?
>> The Lord. Fear not your wedness.
Acts nine.
You see this little example here?
Acts the nine.
So nice to see all the children today
too. All the children here today. No
children class.
Praise the Lord.
Happy parents day.
No chairs left.
>> Acts 9, we're going to pick up at verse
26.
Understanding the fear of the Lord.
Brothers and sisters, let's see this
right here. This this when Saul who sir
named Paul used to be they used to be
afraid of him because he would bring
havoc among the church. Brothers and
sisters,
So let's look at this story right here.
Let's read this. We're going to pick it
up at verse uh 26. What it say?
>> And when Saul was come to Jerusalem, he
assayed to join himself to the
disciples.
>> This was after he had converted right
here. After the Lord put them knives on
his head
>> and b he was like, you know what? Yes.
Let's get to Jerusalem.
>> Read, brother.
>> But they were all afraid of him.
>> They were what?
>> Afraid of him.
>> Uhhuh. and believed not that he was a
disciple.
>> And they believed not that he was a
disciple because he used to put that he
used to wreck havoc on the church.
>> But guess what? Some people believe that
about you. They knew who you used to be.
>> Well, well,
>> and they Oh, they see ain't no way.
That's they look at me like ain't no
way.
>> They may look at you, ain't no way.
>> But guess what? You ain't trying to
impress them. No way.
>> Read. But Barnabas took him and brought
him to the to the apostles and declared
unto them how he had seen the Lord in
the way and that he had spoken to him
and how he had preached boldly at
Damascus in the name of Jesus.
>> Yeah. He had a witness with a Bible who
the Lord used to uh touch him and get
his eyesight back. Read, brother.
>> And he was with them coming in and going
out of Jerusalem.
>> Yes, sir. And he spake boldly in the
name of the Lord Jesus and disputed
against the Grecians, but they went
about to slay.
>> Hold on. He weren't afraid to speak
boldly against the Grecians.
>> No, because he didn't fear man.
>> And and guess what? It was a consequence
of speaking boldly against them. They
wanted to do what?
>> Kill him.
>> They wanted to kill him.
>> But the Lord got a plan. Read. which
when the brethren knew, they brought him
down to Cesar and sent him forth to
Tarsus.
>> Then what?
>> And the then had the churches rest
throughout all Judea and Galilee and
Samaria and were edified.
>> So all the churches were had rest
throughout Judea, Galilee, and Samaria.
And were edified and doing what?
>> And walking in the fear of the Lord and
in the comfort of the Holy Ghost were
multiplied.
>> Man, look at that. That comes with the
fear of the Lord. Brothers and sisters,
if you ain't have the fear of the Lord,
you ain't gonna increase because you
ain't gonna be obedient.
>> The Lord ain't gonna bless you because
you are not going to be obedient if you
don't have his fear.
>> We fear a lot of things, brothers and
sist
your spouse to fear you. You fear your
boss. You want your employees to fear
you.
Ah,
>> serve your God and fear your God,
brothers and sisters.
>> Amen.
>> He said to make your enemies even at
peace with you,
>> you do right by the Lord, everything
else going to work out the way it it is
supposed to work out. Not how you want
it to work out. It's going to work out
how it's supposed to work out. He may
need a little knot on the head so that
you won't get too big,
>> right?
>> Every now and then.
>> Where?
>> That was the end of 31.
>> End of 31. Yes sir.
>> Genesis
>> Genesis 20 and2.
>> Yes sir.
>> Let's see how to fear God.
>> How do I fear the Lord?
Let's see if it's in a poetry. Do you
use poetry to fear the Lord?
>> The fear of the God. No.
>> We're going to see how you fear the
Lord. Genesis 20 and2.
says 22 and verse one. 22 and1
22 verse it is on the screen.
That's
[laughter]
I love teaching it here in Houston.
>> 22 and1 brother when you get it what it
say.
>> Yes sir.
>> And it came to pass after these things
that God did tempt Abraham.
>> God did tempt Abraham.
>> Read.
>> And said unto him, Abraham. And he said,
Behold, here I am.
>> Uhhuh. And he said, "Take now thy son,
thine only son, Isaac, whom thou lovest,
and get thee into the land of Moriah,
and offer him therefore a burnt offering
upon one of the mountains which I will
tell thee of."
>> Offer upon one of the mountains which I
will tell thee of. Skip down to verse 8
and read that, my brother.
>> And Abraham said, "My son, God will
provide himself a lamb for a burnt
offering." So they went both of them
together
>> cuz Isaac like, "Hey, I see all you got
but the wood, but uh where a lamb at for
the offering."
>> Yeah. Isaac, why? He observe. Okay.
Okay. Okay.
U
where the lamb at?
>> Our Lord will provide.
>> Oh, okay. Let's go.
>> Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Where we at?
>> We was the end of eight.
>> End. Keep reading.
>> And they came to the place which God had
told him. And Abraham built an altar
there and laid and laid the wood in
order and bound Isaac his son and laid
him on the altar upon the wood.
>> I want to hit something real quick. It
says at the beginning of the night they
came to a place which God had told them
of and Abraham built an altar there.
Abraham went exactly where the Lord told
him to go.
>> He didn't wait two or three days before
he started make that journey, right?
>> He got up and went right away. He let's
get up, man. Get that stuff together.
Let's go. Hey, pop. What? Uh, no. Don't
worry about the Lord provided. Let's go.
Right. Went right to the spot where he
told him. And when he got there, he
bound up Isaac, his son. Let me talk to
you for a little bit, Isaac. You know,
the Lord had said that uh he ain't going
THROUGH NO LIKE BOUND HIM UP. LET'S GET
HIM UP HERE. LET'S GET THIS thing going.
Read, brother.
>> And Abraham stretched forth his hand and
took the knife to slay his son.
>> Abraham ain't playing like y'all want to
play cuz Abraham understand and fear
him. Who is God? He fear God.
>> Read.
>> And the angel of the Lord called unto
him out of heaven and said, Abraham,
Abraham. And he said, here am I.
>> Abraham was about his father's business.
The angel had to call twice. Abraham,
Abraham.
>> Hey,
>> don't do that to the kid.
>> Abraham, Abraham. Because Abraham is in
fear mode right now.
>> He in obey mode.
>> Yes, sir.
>> 12.
>> 12. What it say?
>> And he said, "Lay not thine hand upon
the lamb."
>> Yes, sir.
>> Neither neither do thou anything unto
him. For now I know that thou fearest
God.
>> He said, "Now I know that thou lovest
God."
>> fear
>> fearst God. cuz he went he was about his
father's business.
>> He ain't about what he feel. We got to
get out of our feelings, brothers and
sisters. We got to get out of that. Your
child don't belong to you. It belong to
who?
>> That's the Lord's child.
>> You just spoiling them.
>> Teaching them contrary.
>> Well, well,
>> for youth,
>> you better teach them how to be the Lord
child. Like, it ain't going to be my
child. What good is it?
Where we at? I'm
>> finish that. Right there.
>> Read still. Finish that.
>> Seeing thou hast not withheld thy son,
thine only son from me.
>> See, thou have not held thy son, his
who?
>> Only son.
>> And you know he had another one.
>> But that's the son of the covenant,
brothers and sisters.
>> That's the son of the covenant. We
finished that.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's keep moving.
>> Psalm 22.
>> Psalms 20 and2.
>> Yes, sir.
Understand the fear of the Lord. The
fear of the Lord is good, brothers and
sisters.
>> 22 and 23.
Start at 22.
>> 22. Yeah, let's read 22. Ready? What it
say?
I will declare thy name unto unto my
brethren. In the midst of the
congregation will I praise thee.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Ye that fear the Lord, praise him.
>> Ye that fear the Lord, do what?
>> Praise him.
>> So we should be praising him. If you
what?
>> Fear him. Go ahead.
>> All ye the seed of Jacob. Glorify him
and fear him. All ye the seed of Israel.
>> He trying to say all because he's he
trying to tell a whole nation. All y'all
fear me.
>> Glorify me cuz you are all of my
priests.
>> But if you don't, I will destroy you.
>> Read.
>> For he have not despised nor uphored the
affliction of the afflicted.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Neither have he hid his face from him.
But when he cried unto him, he heard.
>> Even though you go through some
affliction, you cry to the Lord. Guess
what he got? He got a big ear.
>> Yes, sir. Where your ear big ears at?
>> Why your mouth just big for you
>> to holl at the Lord?
>> Where your ears at for your brother and
your sisters?
>> Where your ears at for hearing the word
of the Lord?
>> We finished that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yes, sir. Let's keep moving. Two
Corinthians the 7th.
>> Yes, sir. [snorts]
>> Two Corinthians 7. That says a two over
there.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Second has E N D on it. Two Corinthians
7 for all these English teachers in
Houston.
2 Corinthians 7
and we're going to read one verse. Verse
one. 7 and 1. 2 Corinthians 7 and verse
one. What it say, brother? Having
therefore these promises, dearly
beloved, let us cleanse ourselves from
all filthiness of the flesh and spirit,
perfecting holiness in the fear of God.
>> How you perfect holiness in what?
>> Fear of God. We can clean yourself up
right here. Let us clean ourselves from
all filthiness of the flesh and spirit.
>> You got some filthy spirit on you, too.
>> Not just the flesh, but the spirit. We
know you were following who we was
following.
>> It was a familiar spirit.
>> Don't let it jump back on you, brothers
and sisters.
>> Keep yourself clean.
Why fear then? You know, let's go to
Psalm 19.
Psalm 19. I'm telling you, we're really
winding down now.
>> I'll get y'all here about 3:30.
I'm talking about home after the class,
off the campus, gate closed by 3:30.
Psalms 19.
Psalm 19 and 7. We know your lessons got
to be short in the summertime. Get warm.
Y'all get sleepy. Quick, short lessons.
>> Not today, though.
It ain't summer yet.
>> Just feel like it.
>> 19 and seven. What it say, brother?
>> Yes, sir.
>> The law of the Lord is perfect.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Converting the soul. The testimony of
the Lord is sure, making wise the
simple.
>> Yes, sir.
>> The statutes of the Lord are right,
rejoicing the heart. The commandment of
the Lord is pure, enlightening the eyes.
>> Ain't no way the world way the world
talk about the Lord laws, statutes, and
commandments. Ain't no way all this
could be in here saying that that good
stuff. Oh, it's too hard. We can't have
to do all that. The Lord knew we
couldn't do all that.
>> What it say was all this. Let's see
about the fear. What it say?
>> The fear of the Lord is clean.
>> Is what?
>> Clean.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Enduring forever.
>> Cuz you got to have it forever, brothers
and sisters. Cuz once that fear leaves,
that obedience leaves.
>> Well, well,
>> the fear of the Lord is clean. Enduring
how long? Forever.
>> Read, brother.
>> The judgments of the Lord are true
>> and righteous all together.
>> They are true. And what? Righteous
alltogether.
>> Not right, but righteous.
>> Make sure you add that T on the end of
it
>> cuz you know you right all the time.
>> Even right-handed. Yes,
>> right.
>> Yes, sir. Psalms 30 and3.
I meant to tell y'all stay in Psalms or
keep your hand in that Bible cuz we're
going to be in that Bible all day.
>> Psalms 30 and3
and we're going to pick it up at verse
18.
Why fear the Lord?
cuz he said to
>> was it worth what more than because he
told you fear because God and keep his
commandments. That's a good reason for
him, isn't it?
>> What more do I need but that?
>> Your job said come to work and get that
check. You do that
>> and then they tax it. Take half of it
out. You still be like, "Oh man, but you
still go early."
[snorts]
Psalms 33, brother. In verse 18,
>> 18, what it say?
>> Behold, the eye of the Lord is upon them
that fear him. Uh,
>> upon them that hope in his mercy.
>> He is upon his eyes is upon them that
fear him.
>> Next verse, look what it do, brother.
>> To deliver their soul from death
>> and to keep them alive in famine.
>> Man, the Lord got you in death and
famine.
>> That's why you want to fear the Lord,
brothers and sisters. Don't fear the
situation. Fear God.
>> Fear God.
>> Don't fear the person. Fear God.
>> Yes sir. [applause]
>> Revelations 19.
>> Yes sir.
It's on screen.
They got papers and screens and it's on
the internet. I got all kind of scripts.
I ain't giving my scripts out no more.
I'm do like Jesse used to do me back in
the day. He gave me the scriptures to
the lesson right when we get up here.
Here go the scriptures to read the
lesson right there. All 1 and 2
Chronicles. [snorts]
I don't get to practice.
Keep it moving. 19 to1. Brother, what
did it say?
>> And after these things, I heard a great
voice of much people in heaven, saying,
"Hallelujah, salvation, and glory, and
honor, and power unto the Lord our God."
>> Uhhuh.
>> For the true and righteous are, for true
and righteous are his judgments. For he
have judged the great which did
corrupt the earth with her fornication,
and have avenged the blood of his
servants at her hand. Go ahead, brother.
>> And again they said, allelujah. And her
smoke rose up forever and ever.
>> Go ahead, brother. Reed.
>> And the four and 20 elders and the four
beasts fell down and worshiped God that
sat on the throne saying, "Amen.
Allelujah."
>> And you know, we really going ahead of
us right here. Future right here. Cuz we
know who's in heaven right now.
the father, son, or twothirds of a new
amount of angels, right?
>> What about big mama and uh little Craig
here?
>> None of them are there.
>> Dirty
>> in the dirt.
>> Read, brother.
>> And the and a voice came out of the
throne saying,
>> what did it say?
>> Praise our God.
>> All ye his servants.
>> All ye his servant. How are you his
servants? Read. And ye that fear him
both small and great.
>> And ye that what?
>> Fear him both small and great. You ain't
gonna get that reward if you don't fear
him. Brothers and sisters,
>> you will not get that reward. You'll be
on the outside looking in.
>> You know, that's where you'll be,
>> right?
>> Keep reading.
>> You want to skip seven?
>> Skip. I mean, I'm sorry. Yeah, skip
eight.
>> I mean, seven. I'm sorry, brother. I got
four different thing right now.
Let us be glad and rejoice and give
honor to him.
>> Yes, sir.
>> For the marriage of the lamb is come and
his wife have made herself ready.
>> Why fear the Lord? You can be with the
wife to the Lord, brothers and sisters.
You can be there for the marriage of the
lamb. That's why you fear God cuz it'll
it'll keep you on the path of obedience
and you can get the reward that you are
seeking. Yes, sir. [cheering]
>> That's why you fear the Lord. So that's
why you understand this fear is good for
you brothers and sisters.
>> Where you at?
>> Eight.
>> Eight. Go ahead.
>> And to her was granted that she should
be arrayed in fine linen, clean and
white.
>> What's that represent?
>> For the fine linen is the righteousness
of the saints.
>> He ain't talking about no physical fine
linen clothes. Look at the linen I got
on.
>> No, he talking about your righteousness,
brothers and sisters. Cuz you can put
some nice linen over some dirty over a
dirty soul.
What good is that?
>> Read.
>> And he saith unto me,
>> Uhhuh.
>> write, "Blessed are they which are
called unto the marriage supper of the
Lamb."
>> Yes, sir.
>> And he saith unto me, These are the true
sayings of God.
>> These are the true sayings of God.
That's when you blessed right there,
brothers and sisters.
>> You get to that marriage of the lamb.
Proverbs 3.
We got three after this.
This verse, this verse is only for those
who got a breath in them.
We're going to start at verse five. Yes,
sir.
Read, brother.
>> Trust in the Lord with all thine heart,
>> and lean not unto thine own
understanding.
>> Let that marinate.
>> I feel I think I I I me.
>> Don't say it around me. I'mma say
something to you. Especially up in here
talking about how you feel. I I I I'mma
say something to you.
>> What you talking about? Both eyes. Which
one you talking about? You seeing eyes?
What about what thus sayeth the Lord?
>> Read.
>> Can we start back?
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Trust in the Lord with all thine heart
and lean not unto thine own
understanding.
>> Yes sir.
>> In all thy ways acknowledge him and he
shall direct thy path.
>> Keep reading, brother.
>> Be not wise in thine own eyes. Fear the
Lord and depart from evil.
>> So you got to fear the Lord first and
then you can do what? Depart from evil.
If you don't fear the Lord, that evil
gonna overcome you, brothers and
sisters.
>> There's an order to it. Fear God, then
you're gonna depart from me because you
don't want the consequences of that
great God.
>> You know he ain't playing with you.
>> Read,
>> it shall be health to thy neighborhow
to thy bones.
>> It's going to be some health to your
neighbor and marrow to thy bones.
Revelation 14.
Revelations 14.
This is a message for every everybody on
the planet.
Back in Revelations,
back in Revelations 14, brother.
Revelation 14. And we're gonna pick up
at verse six. We're going to read six
and seven.
Say, see they read.
>> And I saw another angel fly in the midst
of heaven, having the everlasting gospel
to preach unto them that dwell on the
earth.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And to every nation and kindred and
tongue and people.
>> Who is left out right there?
>> Nobody.
>> Look what has Look what the message is
to every nation. people to read,
>> saying with a loud voice,
>> what did it say?
>> Fear Godhu
>> and give glory to him.
>> Yes, sir.
>> For the hour of his judgment is come and
worship him that made heaven and earth
and sea and the fountains of water.
>> Man, that's a that's a consistent
message throughout, right?
>> It's consistent throughout from Genesis
to Revelations, brothers and sisters.
It's consistent. And that's one thing I
love about this God. He consistent.
>> As a old coach, I love players who were
consistent. I don't want players to be
here one day, next time they down here.
>> I don't like people here one time and
they attitude down here the next day. Be
consistent.
>> The Lord want you to be consistent.
You're supposed to be like him. Don't be
emotional being all the time
>> cuz you going to be consistent in that
lake of fire.
>> He's going to be consistently burning.
He's going to be consistently biting on
you.
>> You're going to get some consistency
then. So learn to be consistent when
Now
>> we finish that.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Proverbs 3
>> two.
>> That right. I mean Proverbs 2. I ain't
check the other ones. Proverbs 2.
>> You good?
>> I'mma add some more.
[laughter]
They throwing shoes.
Proverbs 2
and 1.
Proverbs 2 and 1.
Look, look, look at how you're going to
do this. Now,
you ain't going to be able to fear the
Lord without this right here. How do I
fear the Lord? How do I maintain that
fear of the Lord, brothers and sisters?
It's simplicity. It's consistent. It's
the same thing the Lord told us that we
read every day,
>> right?
They they hand in hand.
2011, what it say? My son, if thou wilt
receive my words and hide my
commandments with thee,
>> if you receive my words and hide my
commandments with thee, skip down to
verse five, brother, what it say?
>> Then shalt thou understand the fear of
the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And find the knowledge of God.
>> If you ain't going to keep his
commandments, how are you going to
understand the fear of the Lord?
>> You have it's an order to this, brothers
and sisters. The God that we serve is a
God of order. You got to fear him and
keep his commandments. You got to keep
his commandments or you ain't going to
understand the fear.
>> You're going to be like, "Ah, what is
this fear? I love
>> you." Love your third and fourth
husband.
>> People love all the time.
>> That's what they say. I I I love her.
This my wife, I love her. Fourth wife.
Everybody got love. Carnal love. You
better have something that's spiritual
love. Meaning to do what? Keep them
commandments.
>> We finished that.
>> No. Six.
>> Six. What it say?
>> For the Lord giveth wisdom.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Out of his mouth cometh knowledge and
understanding.
>> So you need to get this book right
there. That's where his mouth is. Right
here. It say the words I speak unto you.
They are spirit and they are what?
>> Yes sir. Last verse. Last place. Psalms
two.
Understanding
the fear of the Lord, brothers and
sisters.
>> Amen.
>> Understanding the fear of the Lord.
Start at verse 10.
>> 10.
>> We got to talk to everybody. He said, we
started off that the earth is mine. Huh?
All of the earth is the Lord's, right?
And the fullness thereof.
>> Yes, sir. So, who you going to talk to
right here? Verse 10. What did it say?
>> Be wise now, therefore, oh ye kingsh,
>> be instructed, ye judges of the earth.
>> Go ahead.
>> Serve the Lord with fear and rejoice
with trembling.
>> Man, he says, serve the Lord with what?
>> Fear.
>> And then when you rejoice, don't rejoice
out of control.
>> Don't guess rejoice. Ah, no. You better
rejoice with what?
>> Trembling. So that's I mean that's
that's you maintain that fear
>> even in your rejoicing.
>> You don't want to do thing nothing too
crazy.
>> Read.
>> Kiss the sun.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Lest he be angry
>> and what?
>> And ye perish from the way when his
wrath is kindled but a little.
>> Yes sir.
>> Blessed are all they that put their
trust in him.
>> Praise ye the Lord. Blessed are all they
that put their trust in him. If you put
your trust in him, brothers and sisters,
you're going to fear him. And only way
you're going to fear him is by keeping
his commandments. And I thank you for
your time.
>> [music]
>> Baby,
feel